The Formation of Team Minato
ふざけるな あの野郎！
I wish he'd stop messing around!
あんなヤツと
一緒にやってられるかよ！
Who wants to be together with him?!
そう怒るな。
カカシはもう 班を離れるんだから。
Don't be so upset.
Kakashi is already leaving the team.
けどよ…。
Still…
(オビト)あの すみません。
Um, excuse me.
カカシって はたけカカシのことですか？
By "Kakashi," are you talking
about Kakashi Hatake?
は？
誰だ？ お前。
Who are you?
俺 アカデミーで
カカシと一緒だったんです。
Kakashi and I were at
the Academy together.
へぇ… じゃあ友達か？
Oh, so you're friends?
あ いえ… 友達ってほどじゃ。
No, I wouldn't call us "friends."
やなヤツだろう？
え？
He's pretty nasty, right?
あんなヤツと一緒じゃ
任務なんてできねえよ。
We can't complete a mission
with a guy like that.
任務…。
Mission?
《そっか。
カカシはもう 任務に出てるのか…》
Oh, right… Kakashi is already
going on missions.
何かあったんですか？
Did something happen?
あの野郎 仲間がケガしたって→
That guy always prioritizes
the mission over everything.
敵の中に取り残されたって→
Even if his teammate is hurt,
or is left behind in enemy territory.
お構いなしに
任務を優先させやがる。
あれじゃ
仲間なんて やってられねえよ。
There's no way
we can work with him.
お前も アイツと組むことになったら
気をつけるんだな。
If you ever have to
team up with him, be careful.
《任務を… 優先？》
Prioritizes...the mission?
((カカシ : 仲間は絶対に助ける。
それが俺の流儀だ))
I'll save my friends,
no matter what.
That's my Ninja Way.
《アイツが…。
Him? He'd do that?
そんな…》
なぁ リン。 最近 カカシに会った？
Say, Rin…
Do you see Kakashi these days?
(リン)ううん。 街で
ちょっと見かけるくらいかな。
No, I only catch glimpses
of him in town.
ずっと任務で
里の外に出てるみたいだし。
I think he's away on missions
most of the time.
ふ～ん…。
どうして？
Why?
昨日 カカシの噂を聞いたんだ。
I heard some rumors
about Kakashi yesterday.
あんまりいい噂じゃなかったけど。
They weren't good rumors.
前に見かけたときには
ずいぶん雰囲気が変わってたし。
Last time I saw him,
he seemed to have changed a lot too.
もしかしたら お父さんのことが
関係してるのかも…。
Could it be something to do
with his father?
何か知ってるのか？
Do you know something?
ううん。
Well, no…
そっか…。
Oh, I see.
じゃあね オビト。
Okay, Obito. See you tomorrow!
また明日。
おう。
Yeah.
カカシ…。
Kakashi…
よう カカシ！ 元気にしてんのか？
Hey, Kakashi!
How's it going?
いろいろ評判は聞いてるぜ。
I've been hearing a lot about you.
活躍してるみたいだな。
Looks like you've been
seeing a lot of action.
何かあったのか？ 心配事なら…。
Hey, did something happen?
If something's on your mind…
お前に心配してもらうほど
落ちぶれちゃいない。
I'm not so desperate that
I need you to worry about me.
お前…。
Hey…you…
俺にかまうな。
Leave me alone.
カカシ…。
Kakashi…
見つけた オビト！
I found you, Obito!
ん？ リン！
Rin!
うわっ！
あっ！
大丈夫？
Are you all right?!
ハハハッ… ちょっと滑っちまった。
I just slipped.
大丈夫 大丈夫。
I'm okay. I'm okay.
こんな雨なのに 修業してたんだ。
You're training in this rain?
あぁ。 アイツに追いつくには→
Yeah... I figured I have to try harder
if I'm going to catch up to that guy.
もっと努力しねえとって思って。
"That guy"?
アイツ？
カカシだよ。
I mean, Kakashi.
いつか ギャフンと言わせたいんだ。
One day, I'll surprise him.
じゃなくちゃ 火影になんて
なれるわけねえし…。
Otherwise, I can't become
the Hokage.
それに アイツは もう
任務だってこなしてる。
Besides, he's already going
on missions.
だから もっと努力しねえと→
I have to work harder or the gap
between us will get bigger!
どんどん離されてっちまうからさ。
その意気よ。 頑張れ オビト！
That's the spirit!
Go for it, Obito!
あぁ！
Yeah!
Excuse me.
(ミナト)失礼します。
(ミナト)お呼びですか？
You wanted to see me?
お前に頼みたいことがある。
I want to ask you a favor.
はたけカカシは優秀な忍だ。
Kakashi Hatake is
an extremely talented shinobi.
しかし ルールに厳密なあまり
配属された どの班でも→
However, he fusses too much
about sticking to the rules
先輩や同僚とぶつかり
問題を起こす。
and clashes with his superiors
and teammates.
いかに 技が優れていようが→
He may excel in technique,
but as a human, he has much to learn.
人間としては まだまだ未熟だ。
ルールを破り 仲間を守ったため→
His father broke the rules
to protect his comrades,
自ら命を絶った 父親の死が
影を落としているのだろう。
and then took his own life…
His death has cast
a shadow over Kakashi.
それで 私に預かれと。
And you want to place him
under my supervision...
やばい やばい やばい！
Oh no, oh no!
GRADUATION CEREMONY
はっ…。
うわっ！
信じられない！
I can't believe you were late
入学式にも 卒業式にも
遅れてくるなんて…。
for both your entrance and
graduation ceremonies!
Graduation is over!
もう終わっちゃったよ 卒業式。
だって おばあちゃんがよぉ…。
But there was this old lady…
オビト おばあちゃんの
遭遇確率 高くない？
You have an awfully high rate
of encounters with old people, don't you?
まあ なんか
最近 待ち伏せされてるからな。
Lately…I've been getting ambushed
by a lot of them.
That sounds premeditated!
(リン)もう それ 確信犯じゃない！
もう…。
Really…
ほら！ こっち来て。
Come on…
This way!
Here is the graduation certificate
for Obito Uchiha!
(リン)卒業証書 うちはオビト。
木ノ葉隠れ忍者アカデミーの
卒業を証する。
"This certifies that
you have graduated
"from the Hidden Leaf Ninja Academy.
それと 雨の日も 風の日も→
"You are commended
for persevering
"through the rain and wind
to reach this milestone!"
よく ここまで
修業と 努力を続けました。
Here! Congratulations!
はい！ 卒業おめでとう！
リン…。
Rin…
Thank you, Rin.
ありがとう リン。
みんな いねえけど→
No one's here to watch…
火影のじいちゃんに渡されるより
ずっと嬉しいや。
But this makes me happier than
receiving it from that old-man Hokage!
これで 私たちは
下忍なんだから シャンとしてよ。
We're genin now,
so you have shape up.
Yeah, I know.
ああ わかってる。
あっ そういえば→
We'll now be part of a 3-man squad
and go on missions, right?
下忍になったら
スリーマンセルで任務につくんだろ？
その組み分けって
もう発表されたの？
Have the teams already
been announced?
Yes, they have.
ええ されたわよ。
それで 俺とリンは？
So, are you and me…
それが…。
Well…
Don't tell me…
まさか… 別？
we're on different…
Unfortunately,
we're on the same team!
残念ながら 一緒の班よ。
ウソッ！
No way!
ホント！ また オビトの面倒みる
羽目になるなんて…。
Yup. I'm stuck looking
after you again…
《やった！ やった！》
Yes! Yes!
あっ！
それで もう一人は？
And who's the third member?
それがね…。
About that...
You're late, Obito!
遅いぞ オビト。
やっと来たね。
You're finally here.
You must be Obito.
キミがオビトか。
待ってたよ。
We've been waiting for you.
ハァ… ギリか。
Barely made it…
You're really late.
大遅刻だよ。
I'm Minato, your leader from today.
Glad to meet you.
今日から
キミの上司になるミナトだ よろしく。
Yeah!
おう！
Anyway, let's have
our first training session together.
ともかく
４人で最初の演習をやるよ。
は はい！
R-Right!
この演習は キミたちの
チームワークを見るためだ。
In this session,
I want to see your teamwork.
チームワーク？
Teamwork?
やってもらうのは これ。
And the exercise will be…this.
ハァ…。
ハァ ハァ…。
ハァーッ！
みんな合格だ。
You all pass!
All right...
では 明日から
早速 任務についてもらう。
We'll start our first mission tomorrow.
よっしゃ！ 実戦で
俺の実力 見せてやるぜ！
That's more like it!
I'll show what I've got
in a real battle!
とは言っても 最初は
里の中の任務だけどね。
Actually, this first mission
is inside the village.
Like finding a lost pet
or a lost item.
ペット探しとか
落とし物をみつけるとか。
うぅ… それって雑用じゃん。
Those are just odd jobs!
A mission is a mission.
雑用でも 任務は任務だよ。
それを ちゃんとこなせたら
もっと重要な任務につけるよ。
If you succeed, then I'll assign
more important missions.
カカシは
もう何度も実戦に出てるから→
Kakashi, you've been on
many missions already
今更 そんな任務は
不満かもしれないけど→
and this may seem boring,
but do your best anyway.
しっかりやってね。
Okay! Kakashi, I challenge you!
よし！ カカシ 勝負だ！
はぁ？
明日からの任務
どっちが多くこなせるか。
Let's see who can
complete more missions.
くだらん。 勝手にやれ。
That's stupid. Do as you please.
You chicken?
逃げるのか？
なに!?
What did you say?
いない。
It's not here.
いないな…。
Found it?
いた？
いない。
No.
It's not here either.
こっちもいない。
案外 ペット探しって大変。
Looking for a lost pet
isn't easy, is it?
だが
この程度の任務もこなせなきゃ→
But if we can't succeed
at something like this,
our team will never be sent
on real missions.
いつまで経っても 俺たちは
本当の任務に出してもらえない。
そういえば オビトはどこだ？
By the way, where's Obito?
He was determined to
do everything alone,
全部 １人で解決するって
張り切って→
and went off somewhere.
どっか行っちゃったけど…。
本当に
俺に勝てるつもりでいるのか？
Is he serious about beating me?
Oh, Obito…
やぁ オビトちゃん！
That cat was on the rooftop
up ahead basking in the sun.
その猫なら この先の屋根で
ひなたぼっこしてたよ。
オビトちゃん それなら
公園のベンチに置いてあったよ。
Obito, I saw that thing
on a park bench.
Oh right, by the way,
そうそう
いい お茶菓子もらったから→
I have some yummy sweets
you can take with you.
お土産にあげるよ！
ニャーン。
ヘヘヘ 猫探しに 落とし物探し→
Finding a lost pet, and a lost item!
ばあちゃんたちが
協力してくれて→
Solved them both,
thanks to the grannies.
片づいちった！
それに お土産も。
And I even got treats!
すごい オビトのおばあちゃん人気！
You're so popular
with the old ladies, Obito.
伊達に毎日 遅刻してるわけじゃ
なかったのね。
You really weren't lying
all those times were you late.
情けは人のためならず。
"One good deed deserves another."
This time, Obito's kindness
was returned.
今回は オビトの日々の行動が
役に立ったんだね。
How's that, Kakashi?!
どうだ カカシ！
ふむ… たった一日で→
All the odd jobs in the village
were taken care of in one day.
里の雑用依頼が
全部 消えてしまったわい。
Right? It's because I'm the man
who will become the Hokage!
(オビト)だろ!? 俺は
火影になる男だからよ！
This is nothing!
この程度は当然だぜ！
Lord Hokage, I believe this team
is far more skilled than we thought.
(ミナト)火影様 どうやら彼らは→
我々が思ったより
はるかに優秀なようです。
You're right. Kakashi already
has lots of field experience.
そうじゃの。
カカシは実戦の任務経験も豊富だし→
Perhaps I shall send them along
with you on your mission tomorrow.
明日からの お前の任務に
同行させてみるか。
ミナト先生の任務？
On Minato Sensei's mission?!
Is this a real mission?!
それって ホントの実戦か!?
Yes. And the client specifically
requested Minato.
そうじゃ。
ミナト指名の任務が入っておる。
It's a C-rank mission.
任務といっても Ｃランクだよ。
Although the risk is low,
危険が まったくないと言ったら
ウソだけど かなり低い。
I'd be lying if I said
there's absolutely none.
ミナトの任務の間→
I was planning to assign you
to more odd jobs in the village
お前たちには 里の残りの雑用を
頼もうかと思っておったが→
while Minato was away.
But there are no more requests.
その雑用がなくなってはのう。
And, I can't let you just
wait around.
かといって
遊ばせておくわけにもいかんしな。
Yes!
よっしゃ～！
これで私たちも→
This means we're going
on our first real mission.
本格的に任務開始ね！
Okay then…
じゃあ みんな
明日から頼んだよ！
I'm counting on you all from tomorrow.
– Yes, sir!
(３人)はい！
Well, Kakashi?!
(オビト)どうだ？ カカシ。
You should be grateful to me.
少しは俺に感謝しろよ。
I'm the only reason why
there are no more odd jobs to do.
俺のおかげで
雑用から解放されたんだからな。
カカシ オビトのこと怒らないでね。
Kakashi, don't get upset with Obito.
オビトは ずっと
カカシのこと気にしてたんだよ。
Obito's been worried about you
for a long time.
カカシが変わった気がするって…。
He thinks you've changed…
W-What're you saying, Rin?!
な… 何 言いだすんだよ リン！
Well, it's true.
だって 本当のことでしょう？
And you always said that
Kakashi was better than you…
それに カカシは
いつでも俺の前を行ってる。
So you trained hard to catch up!
だから それに追いつくんだって
ずっと１人で修業してたじゃない。
い… 言ってねえし!!
してねえし！ 気のせいだし!!
Did not! I never said that!
You're imagining things!
はい 仲直りの握手。
みんな同じチームなんだから。
Come on, let's all shake hands.
We're on the same team now.
I'm not shaking hands with this guy!
誰が コイツと握手なんて…。
Really…
もう… しようがないわね。
You're both hopeless!
じゃ 私が２人をつなぐわ。
Then…
I'll connect the both of you.
((ミナト : いいかい？
今回の任務は他里の忍の護衛だ。
Okay guys, for this mission,
we will be escorting shinobi
from another village.
その１人が 密書を持っている。
One of them is carrying
a secret missive.
つまり それを守るわけだね。
CONFIDENTIAL
Namely, that's what we are guarding.
依頼の里からも３人の護衛がつく。
There will also be three other escorts
from the requesting village.
万が一 戦闘になったら→
If fighting breaks out…
First and foremost, I want you three
to make sure you're safe.
キミたちは 第一に
身の安全をはかってほしい。
(わかったね？))
Understood?
よ～し！ この任務で大活躍して
一気に火影になってやるぜ！
All right!
I'm gonna show my stuff big-time
and make it to Hokage!
そんな簡単に
なれるわけないでしょ。
It's not going to be that easy.
オビト お前は ミナト先生の話を
聞いてなかったのか？
Obito, were you even listening
to Minato Sensei?
俺たちのバトルは なしだ。
We are not to engage in
any kind of battle.
それに ミナト先生がいるのに
俺たちが戦っても足手まといだ。
Besides, we'd only get
in Minato Sensei's way.
あの先生 そんなすげぇのか？
Is he really that amazing?
木ノ葉の黄色い閃光を
知らないのか？
Haven't you ever heard of
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf?
I have.
私 聞いたことがあるわ。
He's an incredible shinobi whose fame
has spread to other villages too.
他の里にも名がとどろいてる
すごい忍だって。
(カカシ)波風ミナト
次期火影と噂される人だ。
And he's our teacher,
Minato Namikaze,
the man touted to become
the next Hokage.
マジ!? 俺たち そんな
すげぇ人に教わってるの？
Seriously?! Someone that great
is teaching us?
なんか やる気 出てきたぜ!!
I feel my blood rushing!
Man, I wish someone
would attack us.
ああ…
早く 敵 襲ってこねえかな。
ったく…。
Jeez…
なぁ 木ノ葉の黄色い閃光と
木ノ葉の白い牙。
Hey, I wonder who's stronger,
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf
or the White Fang of the Leaf?
どっちが強いのかな？
えっ？
オ… オビト。
O-Obito!
木ノ葉の里には 白い牙って
呼ばれた英雄がいたらしいぜ。
The Hidden Leaf had a hero
named the White Fang.
里を守って
殉職しちまったらしいけど…。
But I heard he died
protecting the village.
知らないのか？
Haven't you heard of him?
知らん。
ん… カカシ？
No, I haven't.
Kakashi?
何だ アイツ。
What's with him?
《ん… どうも様子がおかしいね。
This is strange.
囲まれている。 しかも相当な数。
どういうことだ？
We're surrounded…
There are quite a few of them.
What's going on?
任務ランクとは明らかに違う危険度。
This is far more dangerous than
the rank assigned to this mission.
ここで食い止めなければ
更に囲まれる。
I have to stop them here
before I'm completely surrounded.
彼らを連れてきたのは
まずかったな。
Bringing along the team
might have been a mistake.
頼りになるのは…
彼なら１人は守れる。
Who can I depend on?
He can guard one person.
あと１人は 俺が守るしかないか》
I'll have to guard the other one.
(ミナト)みんな聞いてくれ。
Everyone, listen up.
(オビト)何だよ 先生。
What is it, Sensei?
どうやら後方から敵が迫っている。
Looks like the enemy is on our tail.
マジ!? やるの？
Seriously?! We're gonna fight?!
Obito! This is not a game!
オビト これは遊びじゃない。
あ はい…。
Uh, yes sir...
かなりの数がいる。
There are quite a few of them.
俺とオビトは ここから戻って
追っ手を撃退する。
Obito and I will track back
to confront them.
カカシとリンの２人は
その間に任務を果たせ。
In the meantime, Kakashi
and Rin will complete the mission.
お前たちが逃げのびるのが
最優先だ！
It's imperative that you two escape.
(２人)はい！
– Yes, sir!
All right… Let's go, Obito!
じゃあ いくよ オビト！
ラジャ！
Roger!
Oh man, Minato Sensei!
なんだよ ミナト先生。
カカシじゃなくて俺を選ぶなんて。
To have you pick me
instead of Kakashi...
ヘヘッ 結局 俺のことを→
This just means you depend on me!
頼りにしてるってことじゃねえか。
Obito, we're going to lure
the enemy without a fight
オビト バトルはせずに
囮になるつもりで→
敵を本隊から引き離すんだ。
and separate them
from the main group.
I know that!
わかってるって！
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
おっ やるね。
Oh, not bad.
I wasn't kidding about
practicing every day!
毎日の修業は伊達じゃないぜ。
俺が全員ぶっ倒してやる！
I'll take down
every single one of them!
調子に乗らない！ バトルはせずに…。
Don't get carried away!
I said no fighting!
あっ！
オビト！
Obito!
邪魔だ！
You're in the way!
《強ぇ》
He's strong!
You're just a kid!
ガキが！
その程度で俺に勝てるつもりか！
You can't beat me with that!
Damn it!
《クソッ こんなところで
負けてたまるかよ》
I'm not going to lose here!
俺は！
I'm…
火影になる男だ！
…gonna become the Hokage!
うわっ！
I did it!
《やった》
あ… 影分身。
A shadow clone?!
You're mine!
もらった！
Not good!
やべえ…。
うわっ…。
大丈夫かい？
Are you all right?
Minato Sensei!
ミナト先生。
This is not good…
《これは まずいね…》
きたか… リン 先行しろ。
わかった。
They're here.
Rin! Go on ahead!
Got it.
しまっ…。
うっ…。
Damn—!
あ～っ！
あっ！ カカシ 助けないと。
Kakashi! We have to save him!
Minato Sensei is still
nearby right now!
今ならまだ ミナト先生のところへ
すぐに戻って知らせれば…。
If we turn back and let him know…
No! A shinobi's duty is to
carry out his mission!
ダメだ。 任務の遂行が忍の掟だ。
Kakashi…
カカシ。
走れ 逃げるのを優先しろ。
Run! Getting away is imperative!
Once we're in the forest,
the village will be near!
森を抜ければ里は近い。
They won't pursue us that far!
そこまで行けば
ヤツらは追ってこないはずだ。
Understood!
わかった。
We've come this far.
We should be safe.
ここまで来れば 大丈夫だろう。
オビトは？
先生がついてる。
What about Obito?
Sensei is with him.
I'm sure they're fine.
きっと無事だ。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
さすが 黄色い閃光の部隊だ。
I must hand it to
the Yellow Flash's team.
キミたちのおかげで
無事に密書は 届けられる。
Thanks to you, the secret missive
will be delivered safely.
いえ 残念ながら
１人の犠牲者が出ましたが…。
Don't mention it.
Unfortunately, one man had
to be sacrificed.
それは しかたがないことだ。
That could not be helped.
だが…。
犠牲者は→
However…h
それだけじゃ済まないがな！
うわっ！
なに！
どういうこと？
お お前らが 裏切り者か…。
お前たちが任務の遂行に
こだわってくれたおかげで→
こっちの任務も
やりやすくなった。
黄色い閃光も
これだけ離れればすぐには来ない。
悪いが
お前たちもここで死んでもらう！
くっ…。
そんな…。
＜夜の港に
影が浮かぶ。
潮の香りに紛れて消えた
あの人の影＞
＜群れにはぐれた海鳥が
かすれた声で鳴いている。